Ismarji Workman

Atlanta, GA | 678-895-0441 | ismarjiw@protonmail.com

https://ismarjiworkman.netlify.app/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/ismarjiworkman/ | https://github.com/ismarjiw/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Ismarji Workman is a software developer with six years of healthcare experience as an ophthalmic technician and surgery coordinator. She is primed for a seamless transition into the tech sector, ready to apply her diverse expertise acquired from a Bachelor of Science in Biology from the University of Georgia, Hackbright Academy's fullstack bootcamp, and Cook Systems' FastTrack program. With her meticulous approach, attention to detail, and ability to navigate complex challenges, she brings a unique blend of healthcare knowledge and technical expertise. Ismarji's commitment to continuous learning aligns with the demands of software development, showcasing a passion for staying up to date with industry trends.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Java, JavaScript, Angular, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Spring, Spring Boot, JDBC, Jackson,

JPA, ¡Query, Node, webpack, Babel, Maven, npm, Python, Flask, FastAPI, TensorFlow

Software: IntelliJ, VS Code, Git, GitHub, cmder, pgAdmin, Docker, AWS

Databases: PostgreSQL, Firebase **Operating Systems:** Windows, Mac OS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Equitech Futures Applied Data Institute

10/2023 - 01/2024

Data Science/AI/ML Engineer - Apprenticeship

- Increased awareness about the significance of identifying glaucoma in developing nations through the development of a neural network using TensorFlow
- Streamlined glaucoma screening by predicting cup-to-disc ratios from an extensive analysis of hundreds of fundus photos
- Mastered data science, Al/ML tools and methodologies, exploring their transformative potential to address global challenges

The Collab Lab 08/2023 - 10/2023

Full-Stack Software Developer - Apprenticeship

- Developed a React-based smart shopping list web application, collaborating with three fellow developers and received guidance from three experienced mentors
- Contributed to the creation of user stories, engaged in continuous integration and testing, and gained valuable hands-on
 experience within in an agile environment
- Improved team collaboration by diligently documenting work progress, decisions, and detailed information in GitHub issues and pull requests

Thomas Eye Group - Atlanta, GA

04/2016 - 10/2022

Ophthalmic Technician / Surgery Coordinator

- Increased clinic efficiency by utilizing EHR ModMed to help support general and pediatric ophthalmologists gather exam data pertinent to the patient's visual status
- Optimized clinic operations by assisting with in-office procedures, ordering lab work and radiologic testing, and by conducting pretesting and diagnostic examination
- Empowered patients and families with thorough education on procedures and diagnoses, fostering a deeper understanding and informed decision-making
- Ensured smooth and well-informed healthcare processes by conducting meticulous checks on patient insurance coverage for referrals or authorizations for surgery
- Enhanced surgical efficiency by strategically managing surgery scheduling for adult patients at an outpatient surgery center and coordinating pediatric surgeries at Children's Healthcare of Atlanta facilities

EDUCATION

Cook Systems FastTrack Program 01/2024 - Present

Concentrated Java Frameworks and developer tools training

Hackbright Academy 10/2022 - 01/2023

Accelerated 12-week software engineering program, sponsored by Walmart (5% acceptance rate)

University of Georgia

08/2011 - 05/2015

Bachelor of Science, Biology

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Name That Tune

Developed an Angular application interfacing with Spotify's API to create a music-themed guessing game

Environment: TypeScript, Angular, Spotify API

Listify

Designed a smart shopping list web app, allowing users to create shareable shopping lists for their next trip to the store *Environment: JavaScript, React, Tailwind CSS, Firebase*

Mind Meter

Created a web app that helps users log timed meditation sessions, write journal reflections, and listen to calming music all in one place Environment: Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React, Tailwind CSS